<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[SEEK @ UOIT DC]]></title>
  <link href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-16T03:13:53+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://seekuoitdc.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[SEEK UOIT DC]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[seekuoitdc@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to Bootstrap - This Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/11/15/bootstrap-workshop/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-15T22:36:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/11/15/bootstrap-workshop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tomorrow (November 16th 5:10PM - 6:30PM), SEEK will be running its second workshop for the 2016 - 2017 year. We will be covering designing a
website using the Bootstrap framework. Bootstrap is a framework for designing a website so that it is presented properly on a wide variety of
screens (laptops, tablets, phones, etc.). In addition to designing a website with Bootstrap, if time permits, we will cover using Bootstrap
templates as well as compiling Bootstrap 4 from its SASS code. Location for this event is ERC1092.
Hope to see you there!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slides From Introduction to Linux Workshop]]></title>
    <link href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/10/11/linux-workshop-slides/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-11T20:18:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/10/11/linux-workshop-slides</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thank you to everyone who came out to our Introduction to Linux workshop last Monday. As promised, <a href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/2016_intro_linux_workshop/presentation.html">here</a>
are the slides from the presentation. For the people who were unable to log back into their Ubuntu user account after installing updates, one of our
members, who had this problem, was able to fix it through the following steps:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Select advanced options when booting Ubuntu (The same option we used for creating the user account)</p></li>
<li><p>Start linux in recovery mode (Exactly how we created the user account )</p></li>
<li><p>In the recovery menu choose <em>dpkg repair broken packages</em></p></li>
<li><p>You will be asked if you allow the root filesystem to be remounted as read/write, choose <em>yes</em></p></li>
<li><p>Dpkg will then begin repairing broken packages (which resulted from the failed update), this may take some time.</p></li>
<li><p>When this is complete you will be back at the recovery menu. Choose <em>resume</em> and Ubuntu should now work normally.</p></li>
<li><p>On all subsequent reboots, start Ubuntu normally (without going into advanced options)</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to Linux Workshop - This Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/10/02/linux-workshop/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-02T17:25:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/10/02/linux-workshop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tomorrow (October 3rd 2:00PM - 3:00PM), SEEK will be running its first workshop for the 2016 - 2017 year. The topic is Introduction to Linux.
We will cover fixing the broken Ubuntu image installed on the UOIT engineering laptops and connecting to CAMPUS-AIR. In addition we will cover
the basics of using Linux, and automating work with Linux shell scripting. Those who do not have Linux on their laptops are still welcome to
come and we will assist in creating a Linux Virtual Machine (VM) for learning Linux. Location for this event is J102 (Simcoe Building)
Hope to see you there!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated Website With Helpful Resources]]></title>
    <link href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/06/04/updated-resources/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-04T19:08:17+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/06/04/updated-resources</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>seekuoitdc.github.io has been recently updated with a <a href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/resources">resources</a> section. This is the section of our website dedicated to helping
students find resources related to their software and electronic projects on and around the UOIT/DC campus. Special thanks to one
of our members, Tadeasko, for creating the awesome <a href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/resources/techstore.html">picture map</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Docker Workshop Slides]]></title>
    <link href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/05/14/docker-slides/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-14T17:02:37+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/05/14/docker-slides</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/2016_docker_workshop/2016_docker_workshop.html">Here</a> are the slides from our Winter 2016 workshop on Docker. We covered the basics of Docker - what it is,
how to install it, how to use pre-existing Docker images, and how to deploy your own applications with Docker. Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Docker Workshop Tomorrow]]></title>
    <link href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/03/22/docker-workshop/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-22T18:22:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/03/22/docker-workshop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tomorrow (March 23rd), in ERC1094 from 3:30PM to 5:30PM, SEEK will be running a workshop on software deployment with Docker.
For those who do not know what Docker is, it&rsquo;s a set of software tools which allow a developer to quickly deploy a software service
(often a web service). For example, start with someone else&rsquo;s already-created Apache image, modify it with your code
(for example your website) and then deploy it on any server. It&rsquo;s like a VM, but without virtualizing an entire computer - instead
it just wraps your software deployment in a container where it can be shipped and ran anywhere. Everyone is welcome.
There will be demos and an opportunity for students to try deploying their own service with Docker. Hope to see you there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence Workshop - This Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/03/14/ai-workshop/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-14T20:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/03/14/ai-workshop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This Wednesday (March 16th 3:30PM - 6:30PM), SEEK will be hosting a guest presenter for a workshop on Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence.
Anyone is encouraged to come, but some programming experience would definitely be helpful. Bring your laptop as you will need to
connect to <em>Microsoft Azure Machine Learning Studio</em>. Location for this workshop is ERC1094. Food and refreshments will be provided as well as
a challenge at the end of the workshop with a chance to win some swag (mouse, keyboard, etc&hellip;) Hope to see you there!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arduino Workshop - Tomorrow]]></title>
    <link href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/03/08/arduino-workshop/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-08T19:12:36+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/03/08/arduino-workshop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tomorrow, from 3:30PM to 5:30PM in ERC1096 we will be running a workshop on development with an Arduino microcontroller. This event is for everyone
and no previous experience is required. We will explain everything needed to begin writing programs for the Arduino
as well as interacting with hardware in order to build systems which interact with their physical environment.
Registration is not needed - just show up. Hope to see you there!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[UOIT ENGSOC Engineering Conference]]></title>
    <link href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/03/04/uoit-engineering-conference/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-04T18:32:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2016/03/04/uoit-engineering-conference</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From March 8th to March 10th UOIT Engineering Students&#8217; Society will be hosting the UOIT Engineering
conference. For more details and to RSVP click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1517085868597603/">here</a>.
Registration can be found at <a href="http://goo.gl/forms/kzHflzueoO">http://goo.gl/forms/kzHflzueoO</a></p>

<p><img src="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/images/2016-03-04-uoit-engineering-conference/conference_poster.png" alt="/images/2016-03-04-uoit-engineering-conference/conference_poster.png" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git and Github Workshop Slides]]></title>
    <link href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2015/11/21/git-and-github-workshop-slides/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-21T21:12:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://seekuoitdc.github.io/blog/2015/11/21/git-and-github-workshop-slides</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, on November 18th, SEEK ran a workshop on Git and Github. We covered the basics about how it
works, how it can be used to manage code development, and how it can be used for simple (static-content)
web hosting. The slides are available <a href="http://seekuoitdc.github.io/2015_git_workshop/2015_git_workshop.html">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
